<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>YouCanYouUp</title>
    <description>Blog site of Mr Ke Shen</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 10:44:23 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 10:44:23 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mockroid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first working day after Qingming Festival is a totally disaster. I spent whole day to debug Mockriod on Tmall android application. This could be another difficult task since the development of some codes to make instrumentation test cases compatible to Atlas. It is never an easy job once you try to make your framework compatible to real world application.  Product release android application has much more sophisticated structure. Mockroid runs smoothly in demo application but fails even during its initialisation in real world application. As far as I can tell that to write a serious test framework will take you months or even years. There are too many unknown factors lie on your path to develop an industrial level test framework. Since my initial target is developing a small and flexible Test Doubles framework in Android VM, I shall stick to this plan. Before more efforts invested in this project, the truth value of it should be measured that is the work I will do in the next following workday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several hours coding on Thursday, though not too much code, Mockriod is compatible to Atlas now. The core problem relates to the ClassLoader of target class. Atlas has three layers of ClassLoader. On the top is BootClassLoader, next level is BaseDexClassLoader, then comes with PathClassLoader or DexClassLoader. The process of hooking is done by insert a new DexFile into DexPathList which is a declared field in BaseDexClassLoader, (perhaps not in this class, bad memory). The very solution is hooking the classloader of target class as PathClassLoader before the loading of class which is created on-the-fly. After the hooking, ClassLoader of target class should be restored to prevent unknown future issues. This should be the ending of today’s work. Nevertheless, on Android 7, AndFix raises an exception which says andfix so file should be 32 bit rather than 64 bit. Mockroid runs like a charm when running its test code in Android7 device, but crashes when Mockroid got compiled as library referenced by target project. This issue should be fixed before the coming of weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday morning, I figured out why AndFix crashes on Android 7. Debugging information tells that Tmall android application runs in 32-bit process and loaded libandfix.so is a 64-bit library which causes unsatisfied link error. According to the specification of ARM 64-bit architecture, Multilib device runs two Zygote processes in parallel, 64-bit process and 32-bit process. When an application runs in 64-bit system, if it contains 64-bit library then it will be launched in 64-bit process or in 32-bit process when 32-bit library is found. After decompressing of application apk file and test application apk file, each library in two lib folders is examined. All library files in application folder is 32-bit, several libraries in test application is 64-bit, including arm64-v8a, mips64, x86_64. A possible reason is when a 64-bit device launches an application by instrumentation test runner, it only checks lib folder of application apk to decide running application in 32-bit or 64-bit process. In this case, all libraries in application folder are compiled as 32-bit library  then the device launches the application in 32-bit Zygote process. When application tries to load a library during the runtime, libraries in test application are examined before those in target application. As a result 64-bit library is loaded in 32-bit process which causes unsatisfied link error. Delete all 64-bit libraries in Mockroid lib folder solves this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codes written on Thursday afternoon to make Mockroid compatible with Atlas is not working. Running result shows the test process crashes which is mistakenly regarded as a successful running. Though a bit reluctant to solve this problem, I have to get it done for the sake of dignity of programmer. There are four types of ClassLoader used in Atlas, BootClassLoader, PathClassLoader, DelegateClassLoader and BundleClassLoader. PathClassLoader is used to load class packaged in classes.dex file, DelegateClassLoader serves as a router to dispatch class loading request to each BundleClassLoader. It is BundleClassLoader that needs to be hooked. However, several attempts to hook DexPath of BundleClassLoader are all in vain. Though BundleClassLoader inherits from BaseDexClassLoader, it has its own way of loading class which is quite different from the way of PathClassLoader or DexClassLoader. The common way of hooking DexPath does not work for BundleClassLoader. Moreover, it is mandatory to ensure class created on-the-fly should share the ClassLoader of target class in order to avoid weird crash. Therefore it is not an option to hook PathClassLoader. According to the source code of BundleClassLoader, classes.dex file of each bundle is stored in a field of BundleArchiveRevision, name of this field is dexFile. Now, solution seems much more straight forward, replace the value of dexFile field as the DexFile that holds classes compiled on-the-fly. Field value of dexFile will be restored after the loading of class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not easy to develop an innovative library. Especially when this framework has to deal with sorts of hacking. Mockroid starts with a very simple idea which is mocking the return value of class method. It is not possible to have a neat and simple way to achieve this goal with the restriction of android VM. Thanks to various open source projects which make Mockroid possible. Before large scale usage of Mockroid, there is still a long way to go. We will never know what blocks our way to perfection only by moving on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All right, Stephen King I have to stop here. Your recommendation of writing one thousand words on each day is so difficult. As a man who has limited talent on writing, the writing of several hundred words has already reached my upper bound. This training reminds me of my first essay as a freshman during undergraduate study. I have to keep counting how may words I have written which is exactly I am doing now. As the word count keeps going up, I may have to stop right here, because the word count of this blog has already exceeded 1000. Thank you for your time and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/04/07/Mockroid.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/04/07/Mockroid.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Weather of Hangzhou in March is very strange, it is more like winter than spring, grim wind blows on each of its raining day, it is damp and cold. Perhaps the best activity on March raining day is reading a good book at home. If you are lucky enough, reading a great book during weekend could fuel your brain and get you well prepared for next week working. You may got inspirations from a historical novel for a software architecture problem, or got a well structured plan for the conducting of team culture building because of the reading of a book about the psychology of group behaviour. We are living in a world that full of knowledge but also facing the problem of information explosion and overloading. People are accepting too much information as well as noises simultaneously. It is easier and much more difficult to make a choice on reading a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are living in the world that have various way to absorb your attention constantly, day and night, such as phone calls, App notifications, TVs, advertisements, newspapers and so on. Along with the development of technology, the outside world capture the attention of people in a more frequent and close way. The first thing you do in the morning when you get up is watching the messages or stories that delivered by the apps. You may download several movies for watching during your way to work or home, or you may keeping pull to refresh your tweets or Facebook timeline to check out what is happening that far away from you. We are spending more and more time on something that is isolated from our surrounding, we are more eager to know something which is remote and strange. Attention is never so rare and cheap. We feel lonely and unsecured if there is no phone in our hands, we feel uncomfortable if we are just standing on a bus, we are never so much eager to know everything which turns out we know nothing at all. Most of the information we have got is meaningless and worthless. After all, it would be much more difficult for people to choose a proper book to read because of the unceasing interruption of surrounding noises fragmented the thinking of people’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is rare, and it is even rarer to have your attention well spend during a certain slot of time. Most people living in a repeated life without truly understanding of what is living. They are often too busy to think about their life. Perhaps they are afraid of being doing nothing, they need to find something to fill their time, like a hungry man stuck his stomach by whatever he grabs. We need to slow down, we need to used to do nothing, and we need to read a proper book to make our brain excluding our minds. Take it slow, take it easy, life requires your valuable attention and you will gradually know what is important for you and your life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/03/19/Book.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/03/19/Book.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>English</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;English writing is a big headache for me because of my poor knowledge of grammar usage. The middle school studying attitude of mine should be condemned. I was seldom pay attention to the saying of English teacher and copied most all of my English homework from others. After three years of this ‘good’ way of learning English, I knew nothing about English grammar, nothing at all. I did not know what is verb or pronoun, or how to place article before noun. Thanks to Chinese way of education, by doing lots of exam papers I had remembered, not understand, enough rules of English grammar. Mark of my English was pretty good in the college entrance exam, but I still know nothing about the grammar. Thank you god, after all of these years, I finally realise the importance of grammar and written English. I need to spend more time on learning of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that in China more and more people treat English proficiency as a sign of well educated. May be these people should know that, in Britain where English was born, after the invasion of Normandy, speaking French and Latin was a sign of coming from upper class, English was only used by the poor. In the 2017 Tech Summit of our company, a young man asks Jack a question in English, though his accent is kind of terrible but perhaps it’s a good way to impress the audience. Anyway, not matter what his goal is, it seems that most audience does not like this way of showing off, especially in such a formal occasion. Then came the next question raised by a lady in English again. After several seconds of English uttering from the lady, the audience starts to unrest. Maybe she realises her improper behaviour then ends her English lecture by pointing out it is not polite to speak English in a group of Chinese audience which also implies the improper action of former young gentlemen, what a smart move. What makes a person distinguishes from the majority is not how much h he knows, it is his humble attitude towards knowledge and willingness to keep an open heart makes him special.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/03/09/English.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/03/09/English.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Change and Automation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Changing is not welcomed by most people, because its potentail damage to people’s comfortable zone. In the early years of my career, changing seems never be a serious issue for me. During that time I was young, vigorous, energetic and full of potentials and possibilities. After four years of being software test engineer, career anxiety rises. The major reason is the difficulty of practicing test techinques in real world test project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile application test engineers spend most of their time in requirement analysis, test case design, test case review, test case execution, bug trace. For any people graduated from any discipline, these steps can be well mastered in only two or three years, maybe more time is required if test project requires very specific professional knowledge, such as financial software. If a STE requires further career development, he has to choose to be a test manager or test specialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The career path to be a test specialist is more difficult than be a test manager. The core target for test specialist is using test code to examine   the behaviour of software in various ways and levels, such as function test, unit test, UI test, performance test which includes batter usages, network traffic, FPS, UI render time and so on. Most test skills seem straight forward at first glance, but many engineer problems eventually rises while implementing them. For instance, UI automation is a very common test technique which is involved in the process of automation and it needs to face the challenge comes from constant UI changing. Cost of maintaining UI automation test codes of mobile application could be enormous, and outcome can be very limited comparing to its cost. Perhaps the goal of UI automation is never ensuring function validity of each UI page, but only preventing vital defect before the releasing of new version software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most automation techniques tend to fail because of the short life cycle of mobile application code. As a result, most test engineers focus on specific performance behaviours of mobile application, such as memory leaks checking, FPS calculating, battery usages monitoring. Indeed, figures of these fields can be more easily obtained and require less manual maintenance. If a STE wants to improve his test techniques, these test fields are very good choice. With the consideration of importance of unit test, the possibility of continuous integration in mobile application development should be explored. Topic of CI will be further discussed in following chapters.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/02/27/About-The-Change.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2017/02/27/About-The-Change.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I start to learn Object-c.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, guys, I missed you so much. It has been two months since my last post. In July, our team had planned to deliver a new version of our app which turns out to be totally off the schedule. It looks like our dear developer has occupied by various unknown affairs to hold them back and it takes forever for them to fix left few bugs. I may have to wait for next bug fixed beta_infinite version to run regression test for nth time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to learn Object-c two weeks ago which is a quite interesting experience. As an inferior unemployed Java programmer, I am quite used to traditional “dot” way to access method and property. Object-C follows the tradition of Small Talk which defined the calling of a method as passing message to an object. For instance, in Java you declare a class and make an instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-objective-c&quot; data-lang=&quot;objective-c&quot;&gt;  	     	  HelloClass helloClass = new HelloClass();
		  helloClass.callMethod(arg1, arg2);
		  helloClass.name;
		  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most C family programming languages, this an orthodox way of calling method and accessing property. In Object-C, things turn out to be much funnier and weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-objective-c&quot; data-lang=&quot;objective-c&quot;&gt;     	   	  HelloClass *helloClass = [[HelloClass alloc] init];
		  [helloClass callMethod:arg1 aliasOfArgs:arg2]
  		  helloClass.name;
		  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can see, the way of accessing property is the same. Nevertheless, calling function can be quite confusion because of the alias of input arguments. First argument of Object-C method does not require an alias, but following arguments has to be defined with alias. I do not know why the designer of Object-C designs method in this manner, maybe he get some hints from God that programmer should be sermonized by his arrogance towards php.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/09/01/Keep-Up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/09/01/Keep-Up.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Long time no see, my dear blog site.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since my last post. Heavy working schdule has debilitated my writing interest and now I’m back. Today’s topic is about the book “Antifragile” which is written by Nassim Nicholas Taleb. It costs me nearly a month to finish this book, you can say my reading speed is slow, and I have forgot content of previous chapters. Following comments on this book could involve my misunderstanding of this book. If there is anything wrong you may send me an e-mail as a way of proofreading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book major idea is about risk management and decision making. It expounds the concept of fragile and antifragile as a way to make better life decision. Object with fragility afraid of variables, instability, changes; favour stability and sustained environment. On the contrary, antifragile object will become stronger and powerful in terms of facing flunctuations and instability. Robust is a middle state between fragile and antifragile. It is stronger than fragile but eventuall will break when persistent change happens.  According to the example story of this book may help you to have further understanding of these concepts. Local restaurants are fragile; they are contending with each other which makes local restaurant antifragile. Human being is fragile; gens carried by human is antifragile. Now, here is my understanding of what is fragile and antifragile. Fragile refers to obejct that has fixed elements in it; the higher importance of these elements have, the higher level of fragility object possesses. Antifragile object holds features that constantly evolving as a response to external envrionment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optionality,  barbell effects and path dependency are three important concepts introduced to explain why antifragile helps to make better decision. Tabel states that risk taking are not gambling, and optionality are not lottery tickets. Optionality, in the eye of fragilist it is dangerous, exhibits the very notion of evolving and allows nature the chose the best solution. For individuals, we may apply trail and error strategy to make decision. Process of decison making is dynamic, wisdom lies in action. Therefore, enlarge optionality helps people to test ideas and decisions in possible ways. Barbell effects means asymmetry, situation with unbalanced upside and downside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end of this book author offers way to make better decision. The main idea is via subtraction and negative. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, to be continue….&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/07/02/Long-Time-No-See.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/07/02/Long-Time-No-See.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Kant</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It costs me several months to read “This Critique of Pure Reason” and I do not finish it. The content of this book is quite notorious difficult to understand. All the concepts introduced by Kant are quite obsolete from real world experience. It may a bit awkward to say that you have to imagine the meaning of a term and set a temporary understanding of it. After dozens of elaboration of this term across the book with various context, you may have a better understanding of it. This situation applies to most terms invented by Kant. As a result, people may have vast amount of interpretation about Kant and his philosophies. It appears meaningless to have a discussion about subject concepts without mapped real world  object, since it is difficult to convincing people without solid evidence. Even with solid evidence, people can still argue its validity by some concepts relate to it. So, what we suppose to do to deal with this issue? Shut up, and do your work. Like Linux Torvalds said “Talk is cheap, show me the code”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/05/19/About-Kant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/05/19/About-Kant.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>English Writing Exercise - 01</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apologize first for my reckless and unproved words here. As a human being, with a proper function brain, I do not have enough energy to verity each piece of information that I received. The only thing I can do is to make less judgment and listen more. Acting correspond to this rule makes me more like a listener than producer. This communication habit has undermined my English writing skill. OK, it can be argued that there is a contradiction between be a listener and be a skilled writer. I just mean it is urgent for me to improve my English writing skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many motivations for me to improve my writing skills. The major one is my wife. When I was an adolescent, most of my behavior was largely affected by frontal lobes, in short I was an assXXX. Therefore my mid-school performance was not that outstanding. As a result, my understanding of English grammar was nearly blank. I had no clear concept of verb, noun, article, adjecent, adverb and so on. Due to the immature understanding of English grammar, I faced big trouble of English writing. As you may now recognize, sentences that constructed by me may have very loose semantic meanings and relations. I do not know how to compose a clear and structured essay. Oh, about my wife, because she makes fun of my grammar mistake, so I decide to improve my English grammar both oral and written.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/05/15/English-Writing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/05/15/English-Writing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve --watch&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 16:49:06 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/05/09/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/05/09/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mark down what to do</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, it costs me several hours to build this static blog and hope I will use it in following years. Two things to do in following months. First, finish the “Let over lambda”. Second use Common Lisp to re-develop LLVM. First target I may have a little clue how to finsh it. Second one? em.. hope I can hold my promise and I will create a git repository to trace the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/05/09/what_to_do.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/05/09/what_to_do.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
